

Md Raufur Rahman

Date of birth: 10/11/1998 **Nationality:** Bangladeshi

, 0

Gender: Male

CONTACT

- Mo 105/3 Merul Badda 1212 Dhaka, Bangladesh (Home)
- raufurrahman777@gmail.co m
- (+880) 1626217134
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/md-raufur-
 rahman-03097a21a
- https://github.com/raufursimanto (Github)
- https://gitlab.com/ RaufurRahman (Gitlab)



ABOUT ME

I'm Md Raufur Rahman, a software engineer experienced in backend development, software development, and data science. I have an interest in DevOps. I build scalable server-side applications using Python with frameworks like Flask.My data science skills include extracting insights from complex datasets using machine learning and statistical analysis. I am also interested in cloud computing and AWS. I am also highly motivated to go for higher studies in the field related to computer science.

WORK EXPERIENCE

01/01/2023 - CURRENT DHAKA

Cloud Software Engineer InterCloud Limited

- Design and development of backend systems and services. This includes designing APIs and building micro services.
- Integration of Cloud Services. Working with services like EC2, IAM, Notification, Load Balancer and more.
- Improvement of system performance and scalability
- Ensure the security of the system by implementing authentication and authorization.
- Monitoring and logging to detect issues and troubleshoot problems.
- Database Management
- Implement CI/CD pipelines to automate deployment

Business or Sector Information and communication | **Department** Brilliant Cloud | **Website** https://intercloud.com.bd/

15/01/2022 - 01/02/2022 DHAKA

Industrial Attachment BJIT Ltd

- App development with Java
- Created a basic application that records and displays the student's name, email address, and phone number after they are input.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

23/02/2017 - 12/09/2022 Chittagong

- Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Engineering Chittagong University of Engineering and Technology
 - Programming
 - Data Structures and Algorithms
 - Databases
 - Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning
 - Data Science
 - Software Engineering
 - Web Development
 - Human-Computer Interaction(HCI)
 - Computer Architecture
 - Operating Systems
 - Computer Networks
 - Computer Graphics

Website https://cuet.ac.bd/ | **Field of study** Computer Science and Engineering | **Final grade** 3.45 | **Thesis** Umpire Gesture Recognition using Deep Learning Approach

LANGUAGE SKILLS

MOTHER TONGUE(S): Bengali

Other language(s):

English

Listening B2 **Reading** C1

Writing B1

Spoken production B1 Spoken interaction B1

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

DIGITAL SKILLS

Docker | Kubernetes | Jenkins | Confluence | Git | Jira | Linux | Scripting BashCMD (Base) | Graphana | MySq | I, Postgres, Redis, RabbitMq | Mongodb / Mongoose | API Python frameworks: Flask, FastAPI - Uvicorn | Async Workers (Celery, RQ) | Apache NGINX | Python | C++ | C | RestAPIs

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Problem Solving

LeetCode

Solve Approximately 250 problems.

Link https://leetcode.com/Raufur/

Code Forces

Solve more than **300** problems and participates in online contests. Max Rating-**1396**

Link https://codeforces.com/profile/Raufur_7770/

Projects

MicroBlog It is a simple web application where user can create account, post something, send message to other user, follow or unfollow other user, can see other user's post, search user by their name or post. This project is built using python, flask, celery and deployed by docker, docker-compose

Link https://gitlab.com/RaufurRahman/flask_work

Online Market This is a simple web application where user can buy and sell product based on their credit.Python, Flask, Docker, Redis is user for this project. This application is then deployed in cloud platform

Link https://gitlab.com/RaufurRahman/online_market

Voice Assistant Write here the descBuilt a desktop voice assistant which takes voice command and performs task according to it.Features are like top news of the day, search in wikipedia, open google, youtube, facebook, stackoverflow, open video.Implemented using Python, Pyttsx3, Speech Recognition.

Link https://github.com/raufur-simanto/Voice-Assistant/tree/master

Hobbies and interests

Traveling

Sports

Reading